Guide to the Sonia Johnson audio-visual collection 1976-1981
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
Sonia Johnson audio-visual collection
1976-1981
University of Utah Libraries, Special Collections Audio Visual Archives Special Collections 295 South 1500 East Salt Lake City, Utah 84112-0860 (801) 581-8864
A0099
Johnson, Sonia
22 audiocassettes, 5 VHS videocassettes
The bulk of the Sonia Johnson collection is concerned with Johnson's excommunication from the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints and her campaign in support of the Equal Rights Amendment (ERA).
Biographical Note
Sonia Johnson (born 1936), who was a member of the LDS Church from birth, began speaking out in support of the ERA in 1977. National exposure occurred with her 1978 testimony in front of the U. S. Senate's Constitutional Rights Subcommittee, and she continued speaking and promoting the ERA and denouncing what she perceived to be her church's political activities against the amendment. After a well-publicized church trial in December 1979, Johnson was excommunicated. Afterwards, she continued promoting the ERA as president of the Mormons for ERA group. She spoke at numerous functions throughout the country and appeared on a number of television talk shows. Her book about her embrace of feminism, From Housewife to Heretic, was published in 1981.
The bulk of the Sonia Johnson Collection is concerned with Johnson's excommunication from the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints and her campaign in support of the Equal Rights Amendment (ERA).
The collection is arranged chronologially by material format.
Materials must be used on-site; no use of original material, access copies will be made available for viewing. Five business days advanced notice required. Access to parts of this collection may be restricted under provisions of state or federal law, condition of the material, or by donor.
Women and religion; Mormon women--United States--History--Sources; Feminism--United States; Women's rights--United States; Equal rights amendments--United States--History--Sources; Mormon Church--Political activity; Civil Rights; Sound Recordings; Moving Images; moving images; sound recordings
- Orrin Hatch, Campaign Tape, 1976; Audiocassette (Cassette 1)
- Sonia Johnson, National Organization for Women, Montana State Convention, Kalispell, Montana, 1979 August 25; Audiocassette (Cassette 2)
- Sonia Johnson, Tri-Cities, Washington, 1979 October 29; Audiocassette (Cassette 3)
- Idsvoog Program, KUTV, 1979; Audiocassette (Cassette 4)
- Sonia Johnson Excommunication, 1979 December; Audiocassette (Cassette 5)
- Sonia Johnson, Donahue Program, 1980 January; Audiocassette (Cassette 6)
- Sonia Johnson interview with Patrick Greenlaw, Beverly Campbell, 1980 February 03; Audiocassette (Cassette 7)
- Barbara Smith and Beverly Campbell, Donahue Program, 1980 February 19; Audiocassette (Cassette 8)
- Dick Norse and Shelly Thomas (KSL-TV commentary on Donahue program)., 1980 February 10; Audiocassette (Cassette 8)
- Beverly Little and Marty LaBrosse, interview with sisters by Cheryl L. Dalton, 1980 December 12; Audiocassette (Cassette 9)
- Sonia Johnson, Katherine Parker, Patricia Garett, and Thelma Adair, Women's Breakfast at the General Assembly of the United Presbyterian Church, 1980; Audiocassette (Cassette 10)
- Sonia Johnson, San Fransisco Women's Day, 1981 March 07; Audiocassette (Cassette 11)
- Sonia Johnson, Sonia-Camilla I, 1981 March 03; Audiocassette (Cassette 12)
- Sonia Johnson Sonia-Camilla II, 1981 March 07; Audiocassette (Cassette 13)
- The ERA in America, National Public Radio; Margie Adam: New Possibilities, 1981 April 15; Audiocassette (Cassette 14)
- Sonia Johnson: National Women's Political Caucus Speech Los Altos, California, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 15)
- Sonia Johnson, Speech in Fresno, California, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 16)
- Sonia Johnson 430-2650, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 17)
- To Sonia Johnson from Gwen F. Johnson, 1980 April 16; Audiocassette (Cassette 18)
- Guitar Song by a Woman, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 19)
- Dear Sonia, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 20)
- Sonia Johnson: Mormons for ERA National Organizartion for Women, Montana State Convention, 1979 August 25; VHS videocassette (Cassette 21)
  Four segments from speech.
- Sonia Johnson EXTRA with Karl Idsvoog, KUTV, 1979; VHS videocassette (Cassette 22)
- Sonia Johnson on Donahue program and Beverly Campbell's counteract to Donahue's interview, 1980 January; VHS videocassette (Cassette 23)
- Barbara Smith and Beverly Campbell, Donahue program, answer to Sonia Johnson, 1980 December 19; VHS videocassette (Cassette 24)
- Movie film sent to the Harris family from Sonia Johnson in Limbe, Malawi., undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 25)
  A notation on the box says, "Ventures into the Interior, Laurens Vander Post".
- N.O.W. (National Organization for Women) presidential candidate Anne L. Lang, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 26)
- Sonia Johnson on the LDS church, Gordon B. Hinkley and the ERA., undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 27)